<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Card Games</string>

    <!-- Main Menu -->
    <string name="Play">Play</string>
    <string name="CreateGame">Create Game</string>
    <string name="Rules">Rules</string>
    <string name="About">About</string>

    <!-- Rules Activity -->
    <string name="rulesActivityTitle">Rules</string>
    <string name="crazy_eight_game_rules_text">The basic game of Crazy Eights is played with a standard deck of 52 cards. Each player will be dealt five cards and the rest of the cards will be put into a draw pile which is placed face down on the playing table. After the cards are dealt, one card will be taken from and placed next to the draw pile face up. This will serve as the discard pile.
The game will start with player 1 and continue in a counterclockwise fashion around the table. During each turn a player will either need to play a card from their hand or select one card from the draw pile.
\n\nBasic Game Play:
\n1. If the top card is not an eight then a player must play a card that matches suit or the number of the last card in the discard pile.
\n2. An eight of any suit may be played at anytime during a players turn. If they choose to play an eight they must declare a suit.
\n3. If an eight is present on the top of the discard pile then a card of the declared suit or another eight can be played.
\n4. A draw will serve as a turn if a player cannot play a card.
\n5. If the first card turned up for the discard pile is an eight, then the suit that is on the eight is the suit that should be played next.\n6. Jokers can be played on any card, and any card can be played on a Joker.\n
\nThe first player to successfully get rid of all of their cards wins the game. If at any point in the game the draw pile is empty, all of the cards from the discard pile except for the top card will be re-shuffled to form a new draw pile.</string>

    <!-- About Activity -->
    <string name="aboutActivityTitle">About</string>
    <string name="about_text_gameboard">This 2 to 4 player card game application requires one Android tablet per game and one Android device of any kind per player, all of which should have Bluetooth or WiFi capabilities. The tablet will serve as the game board, and each of the player’s devices will contain their hands of cards. Each player will connect to the tablet via Wifi or Bluetooth, depending on the chosen option in the application preferences.\n\nTo start a game, press Create Game on the tablet that you will be using as your game board. If you device is large enough to act as a tablet, it will have the option to join a game as well. All of the players’ devices have a button that says Play on their Main Menu, which they should press to join a game. If Bluetooth is currently selected in the preferences, a list of nearby devices will display for the user to choose from. If WiFi is the type of connection a player will enter the IP address of the device they wish to connect to. They should then select the tablet’s Bluetooth ID or enter the IP address in the prompt. The IP address or the Bluetooth name will appear in the top left corner of tablet screen. Once a connection has been established between the tablet and a device, the player will be prompted to enter their name. Once all connected players have entered their name, the Start button will turn Yellow, indicating the game can begin.\n\nA preferences page is also available from the home screen. To get to this page, touch the wrench button that is displayed to the left of the game title on the Main Menu. This page will allow a player to set their language locale, change the number and difficulty of computer player, change connection type and modify the sound settings of the game.</string>

    <!-- Pause Menu Activity -->
    <string name="pauseGameTitle">Pause</string>

    <!-- Quit Application Activity -->
    <string name="exit_application">Are you sure you want to quit the application?</string>

    <!-- Quit Game Activity -->
    <string name="quit">Are you sure you want to quit the current game?</string>

    <!-- Generic Strings -->
    <string name="yes">Yes</string>
    <string name="no">No</string>
    <string name="main_menu">Main Menu</string>

    <!-- Device List -->
    <string name="scanning">Scanning for Devices</string>
    <string name="no_devices_found">No devices found</string>
    <string name="title_device_list">Device List</string>

    <!-- Connect Screen Handheld -->
    <string name="waitingForGame">Waiting for game to begin…</string>

    <!-- Show Cards Activity -->
    <string name="Draw">Draw</string>

    <!-- Select Suit Activity -->
    <string name="selectsuit">Please select a suit</string>

    <!-- Pause Activity -->
    <string name="gamePaused">Paused</string>

    <!-- Disconnected Activity -->
    <string name="waiting">Waiting to reconnect…</string>

    <!-- Game Results -->
    <string name="winner">You Won!</string>
    <string name="loser">You Lost</string>

    <!-- Enter Name Activity -->
    <string name="enter_name">Please enter your name</string>
    <string name="ok">OK</string>
    <string name="enter_name_here">Enter your name here</string>
    <string name="default_name">Anonymous</string>

    <!-- Connect Devices -->
    <string name="start">Start</string>
    <string name="deviceName">Device Name: </string>
    <string name="connecting">Connecting…</string>

    <!-- Gameboard Activity -->
    <string name="player_1">Player 1</string>
    <string name="player_2">Player 2</string>
    <string name="player_3">Player 3</string>
    <string name="player_4">Player 4</string>

    <!-- Disconnected Player -->
    <string name="reconnect">Reconnect</string>
    <string name="drop_player">Drop Player</string>
    <string name="player_lost">A player has been disconnected</string>

    <!-- Pause Activity -->
    <string name="resume">Resume</string>

    <!-- Preferences Activity -->
    <string name="preferencesActivityTitle">Preferences</string>
    <string name="Volume">Game Volume</string>
    <string name="soundEffects">Sound Effects</string>
    <string name="SpeechVolume">Speech Volume</string>
    <string name="NumComputers">Maximum Number of Computer Players</string>
    <string name="difficultyComputers">Difficulty of Computers</string>
    <string name="lang">Locale</string>
    <string name="Game">Game</string>
    <string name="connectionType">Connection Type</string>

    <!-- Game Results Activity -->
    <string name="playerNWon">%s Wins!</string>
    <string name="congratulationMessage">Congratulations %s! You Won!</string>

    <string-array name="computer_difficulty_array">
        <item>Easy</item>
        <item>Medium</item>
        <item>Hard</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="num_computer_array">
        <item>0</item>
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="game_array">
        <item>Crazy Eights</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>